Hola
y da la bienvenida a todos al activo
laboratorio de inferencia
Esto es una sesión especial de Active Inference
Está en streaming marzo
Segundo de 2021 y este es nuestro primer trimestre
mesa redonda
para el círculo de Active Inference así
debería ser bastante divertido
y una bienvenida única al flujo activo
laboratorio de inferencia, todos
Somos un laboratorio en línea participativo que es
comunicando
aprendizaje y práctica de la inferencia activa aplicada
la inferencia que puedes encontrar
en nuestro sitio web, Twitter a través de correo electrónico.
canal de Youtube
nuestras claves o nuestros equipos de Discord que
vamos a entrar
más tarde en el stream si te interesa
sobre lo que cada uno de estos diferentes
las plataformas son para lo vamos a conseguir
ahí
Esto es una grabación y un archivo en vivo archivado".
transmita por favor que nos proporcione
retroalimentación para que podamos mejorar en nuestros
Trabajar con todos los orígenes y perspectivas
están bienvenidos aquí y vamos a
utiliza las normas de etiqueta para vídeos en directo
transmisiones que incluyen el silencio
utilizando un comportamiento de discurso respetuoso
vamos a tomar
retrocede un paso y mira dónde estamos
el 2 de marzo está en nuestro calendario y aquí
Estamos con nuestro primer trimestre
mesa redonda
ha sido un año bastante interesante con
dos meses
de las discusiones semanales y un par de otras
las cosas que veremos
pero para mantener los artículos
dos por mes y para mantenerlo bien.
y no tener uno y dos que
romper por meses
insertamos algunas mesas redondas trimestrales
y así estamos aquí en el primero
los objetivos de la mesa redonda trimestral
al menos para hoy son los primeros
Resume los resultados
de nuestra actividad trimestral en segundo lugar
para mostrar ante un público amplio lo que somos
trabajando en y
haciendo y aprendiendo y luego tercero
continúa
y amplifiquemos nuestra llamada para participar
a través del tiempo así que si estás viendo
Vivan, eso es genial, esperamos con ansias
tus comentarios y preguntas en el directo
conversación
si lo estás viendo en reanudación no lo es
es demasiado tarde para involucrarse porque ya
todavía estar por ahí
y así si sigues interesado/a entonces
seguiremos ahí
las secciones que vamos a cubrir hoy
alrededor
y tengamos presentaciones entonces vamos a
adopten una perspectiva estratégica sobre lo que la
laboratorio de inferencia activa
es y dame un poco de narrativa
información para aquellos que puedan estar
curioso
entonces vamos a entrar en actualizaciones de
cada uno de nuestros tres órganos organizativos
que son
dominios y herramientas de edu . com y dot tools, y entonces
En el futuro, simplemente repasaremos algunas ideas sobre
pasos siguientes y las necesidades de cada uno
las unidades principales del circuito
sin más preámbulos estamos en el
introducción y los calentamientos
Nos vamos a pasear y presentar.
nosotros y usaremos nuestro
un enfoque regular que es simplemente el primero
lo haremos simplemente
diga hola como queramos para dar
información sobre sí misma
y luego pasarlo a alguien que no lo haya.
dicho y luego después de que todos hayan
se presentó
usaremos la función de levantar la mano en
Jitsi
repasaré algunas de estas actividades de calentamiento
preguntas y será genial escucharlas
de todos
mi nombre es daniel friedman soy un
posdoctoral
en California y han estado
haciendo la mayoría de estas transmisiones en vivo para
laboratorio de inferencia activa
y estoy deseando esto
primera mesa redonda trimestral
y se lo pasaré a sasha
hola mi nombre es sasha soy una
Estudiante de doctorado en neurociencia
y tiene su sede en Davis, California
y sí, solo estoy esperando
revisando
¿qué ha pasado en el último trimestre y?
um
Invitando a gente a unirse.
y se lo pasaré a alex
gracias hola a todos eh soy alex welkin
Estoy en Moscú, Rusia, investigando.
escuela de gestión de sistemas
también coorganizador de active
laboratorio de inferencia
intentaremos unificar el enfoque de
marco teórico de inferencia activa y sistemas
marco de ingeniería
y se lo paso a scott
gracias alex mi nombre es scott david
soy el director del
iniciativa de investigación sobre riesgos de información en
La Universidad de Washington
Laboratorio de física aplicada estamos usando activo
conceptos de inferencia y tratando de aprender
conceptos de inferencia activa para usar en nuestros
trabajando con información
estructuras de mitigación de riesgos la pasaré
a Stephen, gracias
Hola, soy Stephen, estoy basado en Toronto.
estoy haciendo un doctorado basado en la práctica a través de
Universidad de Canterbury, Christchurch
que se ha transformado más en
métodológico
PhD mientras exploro enfoques espaciales
para comprender y cómo eso puede ayudar
Teatro para el desarrollo de las artes de la discapacidad
y
algo como una comunidad de múltiples escalas
desarrollo e inferencia activa
es realmente una forma muy poderosa de hacer
eso
pero este laboratorio está realmente ayudando porque
es un muy
un área nueva y compleja así que estoy muy
agradecido por
la forma en que está ayudando a conseguir realmente
meternos al lío
y se lo pasaré a evan
Hola, esto es
Estoy en Rusia, Moscú y yo
Me alegra estar aquí, me siento feliz por ello.
Tenemos la primera mesa redonda y mirad.
adelante
Repetir lo que hemos hecho.
el año pasado genial
cosas divertidas, me gusta que todos lo disfruten
contextos diferentes
Algunos de nosotros estamos en una pequeña caminata por la nieve.
otros de nosotros estamos en nuestra despensa
para que podamos revisar un poco de
Estas preguntas de calentamiento
ya sea las preguntas qué es un
experiencia interesante o memorable
eso ocurrió a través de la inferencia activa
labor discord y luego la misma pregunta
que realmente preguntamos
en las discusiones sobre los artículos que
es lo que es algo
te preguntas o te gustaría
han resuelto reducir su incertidumbre en
al final de la discusión de hoy
Cualquiera puede levantar la mano pero diría
uno
muy interesante y memorable
La experiencia fue
la discusión completa sobre el realismo
y un instrumentalismo que no lo era
en mi radar no era una dialéctica ni un
la dicotomía que había oído o estado
Familiarizado/a a pesar de
aprendiendo sobre ciencia y filosofía
y así para que haya
una secuencia de artículos en los que trabajamos
juntos incluyendo
El trabajo de Mel Andrews y luego.
con
un artículo de vanessa e hippólita sobre
ese tipo de arco en la literatura
está influyendo en nuestra práctica como laboratorio
por
avanzando nuestra comprensión colectiva
sobre cómo el realismo y el instrumentalismo
trabajaron juntos
y luego la forma en que ese discurso fue
ocurriendo en vivo en transmisiones y
No vivas en los streams y en textos basados.
la discusión fue como muy
multimodal y es interesante ver cómo
se inclina un poco y vuelve a
cambiando nuestra acción no solo cómo nosotros
piensa
alex
Sí, gracias por lo más emocionante
cosa
es para conocer a muchas personas que se unieron
a nuestros canales de comunicación y
Siganos y nuestras actividades
y empezando a participar en diferentes
tipos de trabajo o
¿Qué laboratorio está organizando?
stevan y luego cualquier otra persona que quiera
Di algo
sí creo que una de las cosas que...
he descubierto que ha sido muy útil, he estado buscando
el papel sobre la conciencia perspectival
un poco antes y definitivamente había
obtuve mucho de ello pero yo había golpeado
un tipo de muro por mi cuenta
y entonces cuando nos metimos en eso y luego
Comenzar también
hazlo realidad en nuestras próximas sesiones
hablando sobre los cinco grandes
Rasgos psicológicos y, bueno, ok.
estamos empezando a obtener
algunos patrones aquí así que eso fue realmente
útil y particularmente porque yo estoy
ha habido una gran lucha con cómo se
me meto en um
abordar desde perspectivas psicológicas
y de repente se dio cuenta bien
esta toda la idea de perspectivas en sí misma
está cargado y estaba un poco sentado
ahí surgió una cosa de hecho que
todo lo demás se va a lanzar
desde mis perspectivas psicológicas pero
De repente
debes pensar en qué
significa tener una perspectiva
o qué significa tomar un
pre-reflexivo más fenomenológico
posición y
mi intuición tras haber entrado en Active Inference
las inferencias que podría cubrir con eso
y lo que estoy viendo a través de
los diferentes artículos de la serie y
debates que realmente
está abordando estas diferentes áreas y
eso es realmente útil
gracias geniales, steven y yvonne o scott
serías
Bienvenido a otro recuerdo divertido de "i think".
La experiencia fue los flujos del modelo
así que tener espacio para hacer preguntas
y
teniendo la muy generosa y
Cristóforo blanco y ryan atentos
smith gasta
cuatro sesiones de varios días
nos está guiando a través de este documento vivo
que tenía como 25 versiones y ahí
realmente lo fueron
Implementando retroalimentación y preguntas que
La gente estaba teniendo y no solo
¡Hola, tenías razón, hiciste una!
error pero la retroalimentación de
la comunidad era como
¿Cómo se podría hacer esto más accesible?
y riguroso
y así estábamos navegando todo eso
juntos, aunque fueron dos autores
en el papel
los que tenían más experiencia así
eso es algo parecido a un nuevo tipo de
colegio de investigación que se sintió mucho más
más participativa e inclusiva que
otras líneas de investigación que se alinean
entonces
disuelve scott
estás callado, scott
y entonces sasha, oh perdón, estaba silenciado sí.
una de las cosas que encontré fascinante
soy muy nuevo/a al
el área es como un
cada cosa nueva que aprendía sobre
Instituto de Inferencia Activa
y los procesos están asociados
con Active Inference
Revela un cierto nuevo um
Perspectivas sobre problemas existentes y
desafíos
y cómo algunos de los problemas que pensé
que se disipaban allí
y luego hay nuevos desafíos
y así ha sido realmente una
es uno de los pocos momentos en mis
vida donde he estado entrando
sabiendo que había algo.
ser un cambio paradigmático
y he estado experimentando uno, es como
de y paradigmas siempre pienso en ellos como
la repentina
¡Ah, esto es como una inferencia en cámara lenta!
un cambio paradigmático porque hay un
serie de ahíos
que suceda, es fascinante
oportunidad para descubrir esto
completamente nuevo
marco que existe realmente
ayuda con lo que estoy haciendo
y creo que ayudará con el trabajo que
muchas personas lo están haciendo así
es algo como descubrir un todo.
un mundo, francamente, un mundo totalmente nuevo
Disciplina
está en proceso y eso es muy
muy emocionante ver eso nacer
es como ver
significa que es primavera aquí la
Las claveles están empezando a crecer y yo
Suena como si estuviera exagerando aquí.
es como ver una floración.
del
del funcionamiento de un organismo vivo en la observación
Estos procesos
y esta comunidad se desarrolla para que yo sea
fascinado por la idea de que el
la comunidad está desarrollando las ideas y
convirtiéndose
esa idea al mismo tiempo y eso es una
eso
una intencionalidad y esa conciencia es
muy diferente a muchas otras
Organizaciones
que ambos están experimentando
y explorándola
simultáneamente
para que la intencionalidad asociada con
creo que guarda grandes cosas para
no solo esta iteracion de la de la
trabajo y el modelo
pero el modelo en términos de un
muchos problemas existentes ahí afuera
gracias, genial, gracias scott sasha
sí, bueno, similar a muchos de los comentarios
que la gente ha hecho
sí, ha sido muy emocionante ver
el nuevo tipo de
energía y estilos de participación que
las personas están trayendo porque cuando tú
Envía la convocatoria de participación.
realmente
no sabes lo que vas a obtener y
no puedes ser demasiado específico sobre lo que
en realidad, eh, ¿qué estás preguntando y así?
ha sido muy emocionante especialmente en
las comunicaciones
equipo y pensando sobre
otras formas de comunicarse además de
el
como reunión semanal de estudio para que...
más corto
quizás algo así
versiones pequeñas y fáciles de digerir de las charlas
así que eso ha sido
estando abierto este diálogo sobre
¿Quién debería encargarse de la comunicación?
y deberíamos enseñar para esperar que seamos
experto
y luego compartir lo que hayamos aprendido o
debería ser algo como una incursión en
Lo desconocido
intenta comunicar a otros lo que nosotros
están tratando de aprenderse a sí mismos
y así, creo que es lo último como hemos
hablaba muchas veces en esto
espacio y eso es solo un muy
lugar emocionante y aterrador para estar así
eso eso es muy y emocionante
algo que espero con interés en
próximo año
de lo que producirán los participantes
gracias sasha, y también stephen y luego...
trasladarse
estrategia sí supongo
una cosa que de alguna manera rebota sobre lo
sasha estaba diciendo que hay un...
la la la la incursión en la participación
y todo eso
como un todo por sí mismo que es muy
Vasto pero ha sido realmente interesante
porque
se están abriendo oportunidades
dentro de ciertos límites en este momento pero
abre oportunidades para involucrarse realmente
con este conocimiento
de maneras que quizás no puedas hacer en
soy parte del consejo universitario
del una organización llamada interchange
por una paz basada en la comunidad
construyendo
que fue establecida por Ann Goodman en el
Universidad de Toronto
en la Oise y estaba trabajando allí
mismo departamento donde paulo freyr usó
para trabajar y
pero ella creó su propia organización sin fines de lucro
la filantropía porque hay ciertas cosas
incluso como
Investigador senior ella no podía hacer dentro
ese rol
teníamos que encontrar alguna manera de involucrarse
las personas que era él era un poco más libre
proveniente de
las limitaciones del rol y así ella
Trabajaría con esa organización.
Creo que hay algunas paralelismos aquí en
me gusta
al poder trabajar con activo
inferencias de manera más amplia
a través de artículos a través de perspectivas a través
Disciplinas
puede ser difícil de hacer eso en un solo
departamento universitario así que eso es más o menos
interesante
¡Genial, gracias! ¡Aquí vamos!
un breve resumen de un pequeño laboratorio
¿101 un alex, quieres simplemente ir primero?
en estas próximas
Presentaciones y avísame si quieres
¿sabes si hay algo más?
quizás en las siguientes diapositivas está bien
Suena bien que empecemos en la siguiente diapositiva, ¿sí?
un simple caso en cuanto al laboratorio 101 aquí
al final de 2020, eh empezamos a
aplicar
onft e inferencia activa en la que estamos
Voy a entrar en más detalles
¿qué hay en un segundo en ft, pero empezamos?
aplicar apósitos y Active Inference
a la organización del Active Inference Institute
comunidad de inferencia
como un nuevo tipo de participativo y abierto
laboratorio accesible
y activeinference.org es nuestra referencia
punto
verás mucha más información allí
encendido
varios proyectos y unidades que estamos
involucrado en
también así como un enlace para la llamada a
colaboración y luego simplemente
Así es como empiezas en diciembre
hemos creado las invitaciones iniciales para
el laboratorio
hemos lanzado simplemente una llamada abierta para
participación
y esbozan de manera amplia las tres
Unidades organizativas que todavía estamos
trabajando con
y luego al comienzo de enero
fue cuando comenzamos el laboratorio oficial
actividades
un merasmicamente centrado en sesiones semanales de visita
reuniones
también varias otras cosas que
vamos a estar hablando de eso
eso es más o menos cómo llegamos hasta aquí
también hay más que decir al respecto
así alex en el lado de la estrategia
tomenlo y sigamos
Desde allí
Hola azul, ok, gracias.
sí como mencionaste eh nosotros
Comenzó a aplicar onft
marco como propusimos en nuestra inicial
el artículo sobre qué fue
preparado en el último año uh
donde intentamos encontrar una manera de
encuentra algún tipo de objeto
en realidad qué nos ayudará a organizar
El trabajo de nuestro equipo y en el extranjero.
comunidad
de una manera de entendimiento
Nuevas formas de equipos remotos y en línea
funcionando
creemos que la realidad se transforma
ya y por ahora consideramos
cualquier equipo como equipo en línea y un
un nuevo tipo de
y nuevos tipos de comportamiento de
miembros del equipo donde la comunicación
Los estilos deberían ser
organizado de alguna manera para ser lo más
eficiente en esta nueva realidad
y de acuerdo con la inferencia activa
y enfoques de ingeniería de sistemas también
encuentra este objeto como ontologías
narrativas documentos y herramientas
que podría ser algo informativo
Nicho
para un equipo en línea
puede estructurar y organizar
la forma de hacer las cosas en el equipo
gracias, genial por el resumen primer autor
alex
y también era un acrónimo y algo así
patrón de pensamiento que nosotros
introducido en este artículo tan solo como un
combinación emergente de todo lo
colaboradores trabajando juntos
y así para aquellos que no estén
Familiarizado con cada uno de los términos ontología.
es solo nuestra estructura
de saber cosas y describirlas
vamos a entrar en más detalles
más tarde hoy las narrativas son otra
tema amplio y nuestro primer Active Inference
La transmisión en vivo de inferencia estaba activa.
inferencias y narrativas es realmente
¿Qué nos impulsa?
¿es este nivel de comprensión narrativa?
y comunicación
Los documentos formales se refieren a ello
podría ser una nube
un documento o una hoja de cálculo pero algunos
documento donde alguien dice sí aquí está
el enlace
haz tus cambios aquí rellena esto
un formulario que es un documento formal
y luego las herramientas son el software
y el equipo y la ropa húmeda
que usamos para hacerlo y hay
alguna sutileza para introducir con instrumento
y herramienta
nuevamente esto es el nivel superior de onft
ayúdanos a recordar que estamos haciendo
centrado en el ser humano
diseño de sistemas y eso implica hacer...
y
f y t funcionan si tienes un grupo y o
y trabajan y no tienen las herramientas
no hay nada que hacer si tienen nft
no es esa nft sino narrativas formales
documentos y herramientas pero sin una ontología para
compartiendo su comunicación de nuevo él
no funcionará así, necesitamos todos estos
dimensiones que deben ser
participatorio y profundo y um
este artículo fue escrito con alex como el
primera autora yvonne en
aquí sasha alexandra eh
mí y luego rj que no está
llama pero uh
también está pasando así que esto fue muy divertido
porque apenas lo hemos publicado como preimpreso
y acabamos de empezar con nuestro siguiente paso
entra en la organización
combinamos sistemas complejos
ingeniería y inferencia activa
con este objetivo dirigirse ¿dónde?
el ingenieramiento de sistemas
llévennos hacia o qué querías tú.
apoya con sistemas de ingeniería de alex
porque eso fue definitivamente un área que
era nueva para mí
gracias, la ingeniería de sistemas es un
un dominio muy desarrollado
de la realización de sistemas de ingeniería complejos
y una gran comunidad en todo el mundo para
unos pocos décadas de trabajo
desarrollando enfoques que ayudarán
para crear sistemas exitosos en
completamente diferente
Instrucciones
de las vidas de la gente
hay algunos conjuntos
de los estándares que se desarrollaron por
diferentes comunidades
aquí se presentan tres de ellos pero
en realidad hay
más artículos diferentes
relacionado con ello pero como
para lo más aplicable y más más.
documentos útiles e importantes
presentado aquí es primero
El libro de conocimiento de ingeniería del sistema
este es el desarrollo de
Consejo internacional de sistemas
ingeniería
con respecto a la versión pasada de esto
documento
se trata de miles de artículos de investigación
de artículos pero es
una especie de documento grande pero tiene
tiene límites del dominio y
si la gente solo está pasando
Esquema de este documento
podemos entender qué es
es sobre y cómo podría ser
se utiliza en diferentes direcciones así
son un conjunto de
los estándares iso están presentes aquí
15 a 8 es para
principalmente para sistemas como la vida
procesos de ciclo de vida y define
procesa lo que ocurre en el sistema y
en
todos los tipos de sistemas que también necesitan ser
creado y desarrollado para
crear un sistema de intereses
y así
el grupo de gestión de objetos tiene el suyo
estándares como
la esencia fue inicialmente desarrollada para
ingeniería de software pero ahora
entendemos ese concepto y
esquemas de
también son útiles para
aplicar a las obras de la
equipos remotos son geniales
muchos recursos que son
profesional
y también moderno y global
desde la ingeniería de sistemas una pieza que
realmente
Los elementos que sustentan nuestro diseño del sistema son estos
el concepto de un sistema de interés
relacionado con los regímenes atencionales de la
ontología de la inferencia activa pero el
el sistema de interés es la ingeniería
terminología
y nuestro sistema de interés es el activo
participante del laboratorio, así es lo que somos
intentando
instigate change en aquí lo llamamos un
nes
cambiar estado estable no equilibrio
que es otro término de Active Inference
y eso se refiere solo a esta idea
el funcionamiento estable
incluso si está lejos del equilibrio de
participante
va a sufrir un cambio de sistemas y
una inferencia activa hay dos maneras
que un sistema puede cambiar para reducir su
minimizar su incertidumbre
la energía esperada de las dos maneras en que puede
el cambio es mediante la modificación de su interno
estados
¿cuál es el aprendizaje y desarrollo o por?
modificando sus estados externos
a través de la acción y la modificación del nicho así
estamos pensando sobre
el sistema de interés como
participante que es una persona
¿Quién está empezando siendo indiferente entonces?
algo
cambios que anidan resultados en el
La siguiente etapa de la persona.
progresión a lo largo de este eje hacia
ser un interesado
alguien que sigue el activo
laboratorio de inferencia hacia alguien que es
Participando en la inferencia activa
el laboratorio
y donde la ingeniería de sistemas y el
la idea de habilitar una arquitectura o
infraestructura habilitadora
los sistemas permiten que entre en juego
esto
cambio de alguien
indiferente o ajeno
a alguien que esté interesado hay que
ser un sistema habilitador
ese sistema habilitador en este caso
hay otros caminos por los que tomar
es un flujo en vivo operativo si es
solo una transmisión en vivo concebida pero es
no estamos en una etapa
en su progresión donde realmente está
produciendo entonces esta persona no lo está haciendo
para saber sobre ello para que no esté facilitándolo
infraestructura hasta que esté operativa
entonces
¿cómo funciona una transmisión en vivo operativa?
ocurre bien eso
más divertido y eso es lo que hemos
he estado experimentando con pero resulta
que la unidad de las empresas de internet
es el grupo de personas que con el apoyo.
estructuras propias
son los que permiten así como
ajustar para un flujo en vivo operativo
que es nuevamente lo que permite una cierta
tipo de cambio que va a ocurrir
en el sistema de interés, es ese
que estamos centrados en
eso es el que nos importa
cambiando y todo lo demás es un medio
Para ello
¿qué más añadirías tú sobre eso?
desde la perspectiva de la ingeniería de sistemas
yo solo quiero mencionar esto esto es un
pequeña parte de un gran cuadro de esto
habilitando cadenas que deberían ser
desarrollado de manera de ingeniería de sistemas
y aquí es
presentado explícitamente que para cualquier
un sistema habilitador debería existir
un tipo en nuestro sistema de habilitación
y de
en la parte inferior hay este azul
flecha azul es uh de otro
permitiendo un sistema en la cadena que podría
sea por ejemplo
canal de Youtube" o "observación
las herramientas exactas que estoy habilitando para el trabajo
la unidad de .com que está produciendo
operativo
transmisiones en directo pero también sitios web y unidades
está produciendo otros tipos de habilitación
sistemas
que se puede usar en diferentes
estado estable no equilibrio cambia
puntos
así que es algo muy complejo
estructura de sistemas habilitadores pero
sin
gestionando la atención de
para crearlo no podemos lograrlo
resultados finales necesarios sobre cambios en
la mente de alguien
como proponemos aquí y debería hacerlo
menciona eso
inicialmente este enfoque fue desarrollado
en sistemas de gestión en moscú
así lo adaptamos
para nuestro laboratorio pero también está basado de nuevo
eso es sobre estándares internacionales
que están desarrollados por mucho más
comunidades más amplias de ingenieros para que
están tratando de
utiliza y aplica tecnologías de vanguardia
El dominio de los enemigos para lo que estamos haciendo
¿Alguna idea o pregunta sobre esto yep
ve al grano
sí, solo quería preguntar, ¿tú eres...
utilizando el estado estacionario no equilibrio
cambia eso para que estés introduciendo
algo
entra en eso y uh, ¿cómo es eso, eh, simplemente?
quizás podrías hablar de eso, quiero decir
porque te da otras opciones
potencialmente que simplemente decir comportamiento
cambiar
que puede ser usado en no sé si
eso es lo que normalmente se usa
así que quizás solo hable de eso y cómo eso
podría
plantea desafíos para ti mientras intentas
resolverlo o
Oportunidades y dónde te encuentras.
con ese tipo de pensamiento
gracias por la pregunta así que hay
ser muchos
respuestas y al final se ejecuta es
cómo realmente se desarrolla pero
abriendo la puerta para llamarlo
estado estable no equilibrio cambio
vamos a decir que quieres a alguien que te cepille
Active Inference Institute" "Active Inference" "pymdp" "Youtube" "YouTube" "Discord" "GitHub" "ActiveInferenceInstitute" "ActiveInference".  se cepillan los dientes todos los días pero ellos/ellas son
Actualmente, el tipo de persona que es.
Cepillándose los dientes todos los días
sí es un cambio de comportamiento es un
cambio de acción pero
será un proceso complejo y no lineal
sistema dinámico la persona en su
entorno
todo el rico de eso es lo que
necesita ser
trabajó dentro de eso si fuera un dial y
podrías decir que lo hagas más fuerte y simplemente
transformar el cepillado diario de cero a
uno
Bueno, sí entonces eso es algo como un
estado estable de equilibrio es un
perilla que simplemente descansa en una posición
y simplemente haces alguna especie de
Perturbación y luego simplemente se queda.
dónde va a quedarse
pero para los sistemas que nos interesan
que son
también los sistemas que esperamos estén dentro
el alcance
el potencial del Active Inference
modelado de las cuales
agentes complejos inactivos incrustados
queremos dejar claro que no
hablando sobre
cambio de entorno no estamos hablando
no hablamos sobre el cambio de comportamiento
sobre su cambio de mentalidad
se trata del escenario completo
desarrollando en un estado estable no equilibrio
El estado de la moda como un ecosistema
Querría
hacia algo y así entonces eso ayuda
estemos realmente claros de que estamos llevando
esa riqueza a la mesa
pero vamos a estar hablando de ello
de una manera centrada en el ser humano
y progresivo en términos de incrementales
cambios
a nuestro sistema de interés y luego nosotros
puede lidiar con cuántas ramificaciones, ehm
las dependencias y las hay
muchos incluyendo algunos que no lo están
nuestro control
y nos ayuda a mantenerlo organizado
y matar dos pájaros con una piedra
comunicando mejor utilizando Active Inference
ontología de inferencia
sí, un seguimiento rápido y luego a scott
sí, solo digo sí, me gusta eso y yo
Creo que también
da una buena transición entre uh
el sistema de interés que estás
trabajando con
y el potencial inconocible
Impactos sin decir, sin obtener.
el complejo mesiánico
pero la idea de que hay que
el trabajo
en desarrollo donde hay
algo llamado mapeo de resultados y
cambios sistémicos que nunca puedes
sé porque es
más allá de cualquier capacidad para saberlo podría ser
Es interesante el uso de la inferencia no equilibrio.
estado estable
parece que ofrece un punto de enlace
porque en este momento simplemente usan
el cambio de comportamiento también
así estaba diciendo para saber que
sea interesante gracias bueno ciertamente
no sé los efectos de nuestras acciones
porque el efecto mariposa tan solo
respirando no lo sabes
El mapeo del resultado correcto es un resumen.
Es una estadística o es una medición
dentro de un estado estable no en equilibrio o
un cambio a un sistema de interés
Scott, sabes tú
produce un cambio interesante en
Términos
Conciencia y cognición
porque sabes que uno de los problemas en
La conciencia es lo que la mente no puede saber.
ese desafío entero en sí mismo
y así tienes esa clase de sensación
no sé si es
ha sido dicho así pero algo de
incompletud de la guía
que vas a hacer preguntas
dentro de ese sistema que no podrá
se responderán desde dentro
el sistema en este caso uno de los
cosas que realmente me resultan fascinantes
Parece que sí parece ser.
un análisis exhaustivamente
mente introspectiva pero no para significar que
no se esperaba también una perspectiva externa
pero sí, con una visión externa pero es, eh
el
Supongo que lo que quiero decir es la cosa.
Eso es interesante sobre Active Inference.
la inferencia para mí es que el sistema puede
saberse de una manera diferente que un
un sistema que no sabe que es
realizando inferencia activa
y así una autoconciencia de Active Inference
Inferencia tanto en la cognición humana
donde has tenido este problema persistente
el desafío de puede el
sepa la herramienta y aquí tienes el
herramienta y estamos usando una herramienta para desplegarla
entender
conocer en diferentes sistemas y su
parece interesante porque podemos
construir sistemas
pueden conocerse hasta el grado
del modelo de Active Inference
y así me parece que va a ser
Revela mucho más cosas únicas.
Aspectos del pensamiento y la conciencia
y quizás de nuevo solo sea un modelo como
diferentes modelos de cómo sabes la mente es
un robot la mente es una computadora la mente
es
sabes lo que sea históricamente
si es relevante tal vez solo es otra
Instituto de Inferencia Activa
pero parece que este va a ser
Revelar algunos elementos del proceso
que nos proporcionará como humanos
con la oportunidad
para entender conexiones con otros
cosas que
también dependen y muestran los mismos
procesamiento de elementos
para que la gente haga y hasta donde hagan las personas
pueden empezar a pensar en sus mentes
como si sus mentes fueran más como una colmena
más como
árbol y su relación con el hongo
y y
bosques que parecen que serán
de servicio a nuestra resiliencia y
sostenibilidad
perspectivas nuevas, genial.
vamos a hacer las últimas dos diapositivas sobre
estrategia
pensando en el laboratorio de Active Inference.
Términos
estructura interna y también su nicho
sus interfaces externas
la idea de interfaces es central a
inferencia activa
con todo sobre el marcov
Active Inference Institute" ofrece diferentes tipos de mantas y
interfaces
también así como ciencias de la computación y
ingeniería para que sea un poco
algo que está casi preadaptado
hasta donde llega nuestra situación actual
estructura del laboratorio tal como se ha indicado tenemos tres
Unidades organizativas que estamos a punto de
gastar
tiempo entrando en las herramientas de updates4.edu
comunicaciones
entonces en la interfaz de interno y
Los entregables son externos
que buscamos lograr un cambio real
y avances en
el cuerpo de conocimiento es un
entregable en un proyecto que es
mantenido por
eso que vamos a tratar en el próximo
es es
por supuesto, sigue en progreso todos ellos
¿son las empresas de internet?
es la unidad que trae lo vivo
Transmisión
y la gente puede estar en múltiples unidades o
asumir diferentes roles en diferentes
áreas
y hay conexiones entre
áreas y um
las comunicaciones también es la unidad que interfiere
sal de
comunidades más amplias así que mirando el
Aquí abajo
hay una especie de esquema tricolor así
azul
¿son las comunidades más amplias las más amplias?
comunidades de
el aprendizaje y la práctica científica son para todos
para que también podamos
llámalo simplemente quien esté dentro
El ámbito de influencia del mundo
entonces hay quienes son aprendices
y profesionales de la inferencia activa en
cualquier
nivel de familiaridad o de cualquier
fondo
para trazar tu trayectoria profesional como la que tenemos
aprendices de complejidad, curiosos por la complejidad
y
personas que simplemente son curiosas y saben
¿qué palabra estás ya en el?
El camino
entonces está el laboratorio en sí
solo uno
Organización en una situación más amplia con
otras personas que están estudiando todo tipo
de
cosas increíbles sobre Active Inference y no
y
las comunicaciones que imaginamos tendrán algo así de
varias formas diferentes de interactuar con
diferentes comunidades
Uno es simplemente conectándose con el
aprendices de inferencia activa en eso
comunidad
así que aquí está la cestística
y existe un grupo de interés especial
de tejedores de cestas interesados en
aprender sobre la inferencia activa y así es como
nosotros interactuamos
y entonces, uno podría también imaginar que
Hay comunidades
quizás sean más orientados a la ciencia
pero también como estamos viendo potencialmente
servicio orientado al rendimiento y orientado al servicio
cambio social
financia todas estas áreas donde hay
una conversación con empresas de internet
como nuestra interfaz así como una más amplia
adopción y esfuerzo e interés de la comunidad
en el aprendizaje
así que esto es más o menos nuestra interna, uh
es más o menos
Estructura interna en consideración del nicho.
y luego simplemente acercarse
sobre la estructura interna entonces cualquiera
pueden dar sus últimos pensamientos sobre esto
estrategia antes de entrar en el proyecto
áreas um
La etapa inicial es la atención sin.
Atención a la inferencia activa y el
el laboratorio
No hay nada en qué aferrarse ni seguir
Después de la atención, pensamos en
Accesibilidad
y sobre la incorporación porque si no
accesible
y no hay una incorporación, no hay
un en el barco si no puedes registrarte
en el barco no hay nadie sobre él así
debe ser accesible y en términos
orientación para nosotros
eso está empezando a aprender
y utilice la ontología de Active Inference
aprendizaje y comprensión y
co-creando la narrativa del activo
laboratorio de inferencia
los documentos formales como los formularios y
los documentos que usamos para organizar
todo lo que dicen los calendarios
si no estás en esos entonces no lo eres
a bordo
así es como realmente trabajamos
y luego hay las herramientas que son
similar con los documentos formales pero
las herramientas
¿son el software y el hardware como?
también el atuendo mojado y el comportamiento
y solo las prácticas
permitan ser un participante y
entonces hay esta continuidad de
participación
donde adoptamos un enfoque basado en roles
si alguien es principiante
al aprendiendo algo intentaremos encontrar
un espacio
donde podrán aprender
por hacer y ayudar
y así es como se verá la participación
me gusta esa persona en ese momento
¿alguna idea sobre estas cosas así?
esquemas
sí, steven adelante sí
Creo que una vez es bueno pensar.
sobre la incorporación con el onft
para darte una forma de descomponerlo
una forma de ayudar uh
understand what bits you people are
trying to be under
um trying to relate to and i think then
once there's that participation
and wherever that can go you start to
get into the realms of sense making
and different forms of sense making that
might be happening
once you have started to gain that kind
of
um framework of understanding and
interaction and seeing where people are
taking in different ways
so i think that's quite interesting
um scott yeah the other thing i think is
interesting here is
in making the um the journey explicit
and mapping it for people everyone is
somewhere on the map
everyone who doesn't know anything about
this is a pre onboarding person
you know some there's some location for
folks
we think it's really important the other
part is one of the things that i've been
wondering it feels like what's going on
now in the world
is that people are moving from data
integrity to meaning
integrity questions so i could say data
security to meaning security
but i mean it more broadly and so this
process really falls well
into that because the data is much more
looking at the
nodes from a network theory graph theory
kind of perspective
and this the meaning is looking at the
relationships and the edges
and because this whole enterprise is
relationship
based in even in terms of the current
state of a node
um i feel like it offers an introduction
for folks to look at the
really the more dynamic elements of it
and so complexity
you know you don't have to talk about
complexity for this to be useful right
people can go into this and
develop awarenesses and realizations
that help them cultivate
meaning integrity and meaning
understanding
uh in the world without knowing that
they're doing complexity
and i think that that the the fact that
this can be helpful to people
um to understand the dynamics of their
relationships and the dynamics of
internal dynamics of other entities with
which they're relating
feels to me like it's going to be very
valuable in this next stage
of security and privacy liability
um limitation all these things where
people want greater integrity of their
interactions
it feels like this practice and this
awareness can help result in that
thanks thanks um okay then we're gonna
be talking about these projects and our
progress
so stephen quick no
okay okay sorry okay so nice up sasha go
for it
i just wanted to say um one thing so
there's
there's three teams and i think at the
start
maybe there was a concern that the teams
would be kind of siloed and
maybe working on their own projects and
not
linked and so i think it's been
surprising
um in a great way that the teams are
actually very interconnected because of
the people who are on them
but also because the teams are dependent
on
each other for content and for
development
and so that's been a really um i guess
exciting and pleasant surprise that
um the teams are going to continue to
work together and kind of bounce off of
each other
in a way that um really isn't siloed or
sequestered
um as i maybe wrongly expected
cool and welcome dave hello
yep and tools doesn't have any links out
at this point but that's just a current
snapshot so we'll update things
um here we go with the update on the
edu organizational unit so
the edu the goal of this
unit is pretty broad it's to create a
participatory and dynamic active
inference body of knowledge
and our primary areas of progress have
been related to
ontology development specifically a
terms list which we're going to get to
in just a second
and the next steps for this section
which again we're going to go into more
detail when alex describes the ontology
we're still looking for feedback on the
terms list and we're
making progress on ontology development
and the
um ontology life cycle but we're still
looking for
ontology experts so people who have
worked in
an advanced capacity with ontology so
alex maybe you want to take a first pass
on the active inference body of
knowledge what is this diagram on the
right
and then what does it mean for active
inference
okay thanks yeah on the right
is a diagram from
it's about ecosystem i guess
which is grown
around international
council of system engineering and well
there are a lot of areas of people's
activity
and all of it we can see
is based on
system engineering body of knowledge so
when you have
such kind of body of knowledge
you have option to create
different educational courses maybe
certification programs
maybe a lot of different stuff
to people to work with to
learn to develop themselves in the
domain to communicate
when you have some kind of knowledge
artifact which you can refer
and which have its own life cycle
but it's kind of
common agreement of uh domain
understanding
between the community and this is a
cornerstone to develop
different type of projects and
activities
and our hypothesis was could we use the
same approach
to develop active inference body of
knowledge
which should also provide us much more
importances
to develop the domain
organize the work of people and make
progress in all possible meanings
cool yep it was this idea of a body of
knowledge which is implicit
in every developed and mature field but
the engineers take it to the next level
and the systems thinkers working
together unsurprisingly
so it's like very cool to see how
there's really a specific relationships
between different parts here
these are actually controlled vocabulary
terms like in forms and drives these
aren't just like sort of synergy type
words and so by defining the interfaces
and the progressions it actually helps
it
be participatory and accessible and so
we just were
motivated by active inference one day
realizing a truly mature body of
knowledge
which isn't just a textbook it's not
just an unpacking of a paper it's not
just a journal club discussion live
stream
it's actually formal courses
certification
standards but also practices that unify
our community so that will be really
awesome and then it says what else
because
we just listed a few english words but
this is something that we're going to be
enacting together so that's why
one option is you know the live chat
that's in affordance for feedback
for those who are on the stream yes it's
an affordable feedback and for co-design
and then it's the actual doing and that
will decide how it is
so this is going to be pretty cool to be
working on with
edu and then we have a lot other things
to say in ontology but stephen go for it
just like to say i think it's quite
interesting the um that bit in the
middle the boundary of systems
engineering so i quite like
the uh you know with the participatory
nature and the sort of
evolving nature of uh sort of
discussions you've got
it's like the right um the right hand
side there is is is the
the more kind of structured formalized
way it's bridged by this boundary of
system engineering with the
system engineering community so it's
kind of
be interesting to see how that nature of
the boundary of system engineering
um relates back to the nests
non-equilibrium steady state and whether
there's some interesting dynamics there
which may be a similar or different to
what's done in other areas of uh systems
engineering
cool so um as far as progress on our
journey
one of the key insights that many people
don't expect
but then once they start understanding
the sense of the word more broadly
they start to see is that ontology is
the root and the backbone
whatever metaphor you want to use it's
the structure it's the clothes hanger
it's a formal and explicit specification
of a shared
conceptualization of a domain that
doesn't mean it's fixed in fact it's
dynamic
and participatory and then ontology is
communicated between
people as well as computers and that's
what allows us to have heterogeneous
and distributed systems and this is a
paper um i think by its ontology
learning from text
by i think yang at all or i'm not sure
and um we could look but
go right now and it's a continuum of
formality of ontologies
so not every one of these terms many
people would associate
all these things with ontology but we're
taking a broad perspective on ontology
and we're starting with the simplest
which is a terms list which we're going
to show in a second
terms lists can be updated as well as
new terms can be added terms can be
removed but
the richness of the ontology which is uh
like a sort of way that things are
related to each other
the richness can be developed to
initially include definitions and
synonyms like a glossary or thesaurus
then looking more like a database like a
data approach
then all the way out to formal logics
that allow
almost computation in an analytical way
on
knowledge relationships which is
extremely powerful but usually it's
quite domain specific
so we can't put the
cart before the horse i was thinking put
the inference before the active but
that's fine
both directions are fine so we're
developing dynamic ontology life cycle
and the stage that we are at in this
first quarterly update
is that we did complete the first stable
version not the final version of the
terms list
that's the active inference lab terms
list v 1.0 candidate
and we've been getting several weeks of
feedback on the terms list
improved it a lot also with very much
appreciated feedback from
carl fristin and this terms list is not
always going to be a spreadsheet it's
not always going to look this way
it will develop into richer
computational resources
that allow us to do translation allow us
to make
educational content at different levels
to connect formally to different fields
to think about how terms are being used
across different spaces to provide
points of contact
because one thing that we noticed when
we were making the terms list in the
supplement which is sort of
words that we put in the b tier was the
b tier words
were like a lot of isms and theories and
ideas and
ways of doing a certain mathematical
formalism and then the terms
for the actual core set that we will
be focusing our language use and
understanding on
they include really um powerful words
like
accuracy action agency ambiguity
attention that's just the a
section and there's less than 90 terms
right now
so this is pretty fun and that's
basically where we're at with
the ontology project which has been the
main focus of the edu
unit and the next steps are to continue
up this progression to move towards
better understandings of our ontology as
well as to use
text analysis type approaches to
understand how these terms are being
used
and provide a little bottom-up or a
data-driven ontological approach
anyone have any thoughts or comments on
ontology or edu before we go to the next
section
all right let's stephen go ahead
yeah i'd just like to say this is really
very very useful
um actually i think even
the process of people um you know going
through these terms they could be an
interesting educational piece
um just like having people explore
how these terms arise for themselves you
know and actually
maybe even gamifying some of this
because in exploring and finding out the
terms you actually
understand an awful lot more about
active infants so it's it's
it's good on a number of levels actually
cool
and also dave thanks a lot for your
really
powerful insights into ontology and just
language and helping us think about that
in a in a
structured way so the second project is
comms second organizational unit because
there's teams there's projects inside of
a unit so for now it's sort of like the
unit and the team are really similar
but when the organizational unit is
larger then there will be
disjoint teams and projects inside of
comms
so the goal of comms is sort of two-fold
the first goal is to carry out all forms
of communication with external entities
and the other goal is to organize the
lab's internal projects and activities
so it's internal communication and
external communication
because when we're thinking about
systems design for online teams for
remote teams which are all of them now
those are what we have access to
internal communications design
and then external communications
interfacing
and towards that end i think comms has
been
a fun experience for a lot of people
we had several projects within comps
so again with overlapping personnel at
this point but
um not for always there um
several uh series that we carried out
so just to sort of describe and
distinguish them the active inference
live stream
is the main weekly discussion that we've
been having
it's publication centric other than the
quarterly roundtables
it's like we discuss a paper and that's
why we have the calendar that references
the paper and we schedule things
a lot in advance for this one and for
each
number of paper like number 16 is going
to be the same paper for 16.012345
however many sessions we need on that
paper and the idea is that dot zero
is like a contextualing a
contextualizing video
um blue as a amazing contextualizer
and we'll be doing 17.0 tomorrow um
so probably pull an all-nighter or
something on that one
and then the dot one and the dot two
videos are participatory group
discussions ideally with the authors
around
also be cool if authors wanted to help
us with dot zero but the idea is we can
invite and really honor and respect
the authors by having them show up to a
discussion
where there's going to be a group of
people people sharing their perspectives
at different
stages in understanding and then it's
all good for participants to have
not read the paper or read the paper a
little bit just circled questions
highly added a ton of notes it's like
wherever people are at
the authors are the ones who put out the
paper and so that's been great to talk
with the researchers in the active
inference
community then um that sort of led
to a desire to go a little bit more
technical at times
and ryan smith and christopher white
kicked off our model stream series with
four
model streams and the model stream is
intended to be like a tutorial or a code
walk through
or more like a deep dive into modeling
because then we can be really clear
where we're doing a how-to on modeling
and then
in a live stream uh regular format would
be more about
like when we had alex chance for octave
eight um
that was talking about implications and
asking some more qualitative questions
about the project
and then the new um newest series is the
guest stream
and majeed benny came on for the first
guest stream on feb
24th and the guest stream is just our
grab bag
our wild card it's like if a new paper
comes out
we could have a discussion with the
authors 48 hours later
if they're available so a guest stream
the idea is on
short time scales or if someone says
yeah i'm really busy i could come on and
visit in
seven months then we can also account
for that so any
time of day or any availability that
that somebody has
who wants to be leading a session or be
a guest on a session
we'll just put it in the guest stream
component and then there's bite-sized
so maybe blue would you want to say
anything about bite size or any other
projects that you're thinking about on
this front
sure the um bite size really uh
you know i have a lot of people like
where i'm like i'm doing this live
stream it's really cool you should come
like participate
and here's this big paper like the paper
that we're doing for the
17.0 is like you know 30 pages long like
here read this paper and join us on our
live stream and people get a little
uh intimidated by that and so they don't
really want to engage
at that level but i've definitely had a
lot of feedback from people saying like
oh you're gonna make it into like an
audio podcast like short like
15 minute little clips that we can
listen to on the way to work or while
i'm out for a walk or whatever and so
i've had a lot of interest in that and
um i think i'm i've got two episodes
already clipped from
like i'm starting at the earlier live
streams and moving up um
and so so i've got a couple episodes
that already clipped and ready and one
more that's almost ready
so i think we should be launching like
as soon as i get them
pushed into the rss feed maker we should
be launching maybe as early as
next week probably so just you know
short little episodes for people to
um listen to and um you know that that
are maybe not
don't involve reading a 30 page paper
and doing a bunch of math
uh but still people can engage at a
level that's kind of
um thought friendly and right commute
friendly
right awesome yeah thanks a lot for
taking the initiative and helping that
project happen and
we'll probably make another youtube
channel like
acting clips or something and then
we can figure out how to make it work
and we'll keep everyone posted through
our
communications channels so also another
deliverable with the next steps for
comms we're going to continuing continue
working on our
series that exist so the live stream has
a calendar
um that's in the info box for each video
the model stream
we're in conversation with several
people as well as for guest stream with
future dates
so that's how it is with live stream you
can schedule it but then in the end it's
better to tell people
when it goes live or after because you
never know what's going to happen
last moment so we just um
are looking to schedule and coordinate
with new participants
of any background or interest if
somebody wants to
give a model stream or you know be the
one who's walking through their tutorial
or their blog
that's awesome and we have so many
people who have written like their own
sort of
um free energy or active inference
manifestos or learning
documents so how to surface that or
who could we invite in an adjacent
community to do a guest stream or like
an interview or
could we do a special other stream could
we do a math stream or a kid stream
or just joke stream who knows
and then we're looking towards the kinds
of communications
that are enabled by the markov blanket
of a remote team
we can send data and that data can be
text
like a blog or a wiki or article it
could be audio only
it could be video only it could be a
still image it could be a physical
object
so what are our affordances as an
organization
and then there's some that we can't
afford
to do now but maybe we'll afford them
later
and then just the last note on comms is
it's been pretty
interesting to work on what basically
amounts to a live stream organization
and implementation checklist
it's just a sequence of commentable
google slides
for now but it partitions
some of the roles of a live stream just
one perspective
in a way that makes sense inc it
includes a couple of things
that people might not expect about a
live stream for example that what they
see on their computer is what other
people see or that noises
might be not for them but other people
can hear it or vice versa
and um that helps us make sure that we
have a high quality live stream
experience for everybody
as well as an experience that is
accessible because someone can
um reduce their anxiety reduce their
uncertainty about
the who why where when and then there's
a total
um direction to continue in
with just how to communicate and
dialogue
so i know it's something that many
people on this
conversation and and in the lab think
about a lot like
whether it's in the context of
transformative dialogue
productive innovative whatever adjective
is meaningful to you there's something
about improvisation
and coming together with the affordances
that we have
to just hopefully do good and have fun
so how do we make that possible
has been what comms is about clarifying
and communicating on
any last thoughts on comms before we go
to tools
um yeah alex then stephen
yeah thanks i just want to add uh
in relation to checklist that it is
a checklist is one of the main concepts
of
and approach from systems engineering so
we are trying to apply system
engineering
approaches for actually
all types of activities what we are
doing
cool stephen yeah i suppose the
the idea of the niche or creating as
an awareness of the niche and the
affordances in the niche that we're
giving
people as well as their their own sort
of personal
journeys kind of a nice way to think
about this so as as
as the list is being ticked off it's
like
connect with self and participants to
bring the relevant energy
so that's kind of a bigger term
than you might often get in an
engineering context but you know that
that's
but that is the sort of thing that often
gets forgotten you know especially if
you're
so it's good to to like have that as a
yeah let's just check in
you know and just get that chance to
make sure that
we're in the right headspace because
this it does take some time to
to reorientate so that's quite good yep
and
the the challenge and the opportunity
are
two sides of the same coin for the
remote teams we can have international
conversations and so yes maybe you know
dave's video blips out
once in a while or somebody gets kicked
off but it's like we're having
conversations that are very special
so instead of relativizing it to some
imagined reality where like tech is
perfect and free and everyone has it
we can reference to what's possible and
then we work with what we have and make
the best of it and
some people their rate limiting step to
live stream participation
is psychological or internal whatever
for some people it's um logistical they
can't
make the time work maybe they live in a
different time zone for other people
it's technical
they have the time and they want to do
it but they don't have a camera or a
microphone or
internet connectivity or something like
that so when we
have a role-based approach to
participation not like
live streamers not a title in our
community it's like
who's a participant in this live stream
today
in quarterly roundtable one which role
is everybody playing
and we actually have an answer for which
people are playing each role
and whether they did or didn't do the
checklist exactly today
probably few did um i know that the
broadcaster didn't
but that's all good because it at least
is there
and then we can iterate on it and that
will i think really
be powerful and effective okay any other
thoughts on comps but yeah we're just
looking forward to
learning by doing and communicating all
right tools so this is kind of a fun
section i think the goals of the dot
tools
unit are again sort of twofold an
internal and an external
view so the internal goal of
tools is to enable effective tool and
instrument use for all active inference
lab processes
so we need to figure out which tools
will work best for
onft for onboarding and participation
otherwise we don't have
anything but especially as we
build more scaffolding for
our lab and stabilize some of the tool
use inside of our lab and have more
regimes of attention to spare
on external views we're interested in
exploring and designing
affordances within our niche which is
all we can ever have
resulting in effective action externally
facing
and also innovating in terms of tool
development so
um tim and others who we had such
great conversations with in the weekly
discussions that
relate to our progress um and several
others scott and schneider
and many just awesome people who came
through there's like
us using tools to make the lab better at
what it does
and then there is the tantalizing
and exciting question of what active
inference driven
tools look like whether there's an
active inference computational
or software element and so the tools
look like
slack or look like email or look like
something that people are very familiar
with
but it's like a recommendation engine
that changes
how things are done in some subtle way
so whether we talk about
implementing active inference on top of
the tools that we know and see today
or whether we're talking about truly
novel
and unexpected ways of active inference
and systems engineering and systems
design
coming into play in the true um
imminent future of online work
that is where we want to go but um
with a couple people and a lot to figure
out internally
we haven't gotten there but like people
have been saying
all of the goals and units are
intertwined
and to use a figure from our paper the
fiatkin at all paper
we're taking a function driven approach
to thinking about this internal and
external team communication
and the tooling for that using the
active inference framework
because designing the system for the
physical
office you know you need the hammer to
build the hallway so that you could have
a certain
connectivity of conversation or certain
architectural suggestion
but the hammer our tool is actually the
modification
of communication pathways communication
being included
data being shuttled back and forth
between parts of a computer
or across the internet also a part of
communication between non-human agents
so we sort of even
from last year wanted to use the idea of
a markov blanket
and blankets or however they end up
being defined with interfaces
as sense incoming and actions outgoing
and so we have
internal team communications and then
external team communications
which are all important sense in action
internally and externally just like
multi-scale nested active inference and
then tool development is about making
that happen
so we're going to run now through the
tools
including ones that i hope some people
will be familiar with maybe some
people will not be familiar with and
anyone can just raise their hand
if they want to mention something about
tool so
the single source of truth from a file
sharing perspective
for the lab is a google drive folder
from activeinference.gmail.com
and this is our activelab folder we have
the three
organizational units.edu tools and comms
and then we have dot admin which is the
uh
minimal administration for the lab and
just like the form
responses that are not part of one of
these other
organizational units but by and large
everything related to these projects
is totally viewable and if people rsvp
to participate
they're added as an editor to the folder
if they
um just want to see the link then they
can comment on everything so everything
from the slides for all of the
presentations to the feedback
for the podcast are in each of these
folders
and uh it's a participatory and
hopefully an open way
to organize so any project that people
are hearing about that sounds cool
or something that they think is an
adjacency or a role that they'd like to
play
even if um just a very
vague sense of what it could be just get
in touch with us because basically
this is our current project
to go into a few specific areas
in our work on the ontology and terms we
used two different tools
we used google documents
as we used with many projects documents
and sheets but then also we use protege
which is a online the web protege is an
online ontology editor
lightweight but pretty powerful and
there's also a desktop application
and this is for ontology construction
and sharing so that's pretty fun just
learning about ontologies and different
ways of viewing
um terms we
use um gather.town for spatial video
chat
and um right now we're using jitsi which
i actually didn't take a screenshot of
we could
do it total uh during add but
gatherer.town
is allowing for interfaces uh
and affordances like movement while i'm
taking a screenshot stephen
just maybe give one thought on gathering
active inference and where that might
come into play yeah well
it could be interesting i think active
inference and the nature of how
we relate into our affordances it's kind
of interesting when you start to be
sitting at a table as an avatar
and how that feels slightly different um
to how you are maybe when you're sort of
in an open space
discussing aspects of active inference
so it might be it might be quite
interesting as we
start to explore how some of the active
inference processes
are ontologically and then how they are
when we start to experience um
stepping into the dynamics of
active impress inference because it is a
a process
theory rather than a static
sort of diagram telling us what the
world is so
that opens up some possibilities um and
uh yeah i quite enjoy
meeting everyone that way so i i don't
know how others find it but
i think that's uh yep there's
possibilities
yep fun and jitsy is a little bit more
standard but it's an
open source video platform and we have
an aws server
so it will cost a couple of cents or a
little bit more per
meeting but then we know that we have
the reliability
but also meet.jit.c is free okay
then for text and file sharing and the
official
organization of each of the lab the dot
admin
and the three units that we have as well
as dot public on key base
this is um a platform just it's not
about
the pros and cons of any of these
specific platforms we're just saying
what it is that we're
using but key base is a really great
platform at the current
moment for doing the kinds of things
that we want to do
in the back end for official
organization
this is like the internal communications
of the lab then there's the external
communications in the lab
now it being an open in a participatory
lab
sometimes it's a little bit hard to say
where is their internal and external
communication because
all of the documents are visible all of
our teams are joinable
so where is the line between internal
and external communication
basically there's communications that we
address to participants and
members of our lab people who are
actively um somebody who would just
directly
solicit feedback to in a sort of
off-the-cuff way
like somebody you might bump into in a
co-working situation ask for feedback
whereas external communications we try
to communicate
um sporadically but regularly
and uh well structuring our external
communications
like having professionalism with our
newsletter and with our live streams
whereas just popping on a video call
with the same people
it'd be an internal lab discussion
because it wasn't being performed
externally but they're ultimately all
open i guess
so for external communication
specifically but
also increasingly project collaborations
just ones that aren't
the three organizational units of the
lab which is our focus as
organizers is the actual organization of
those lab units and
incrementing those systems and including
participation in a lab
and then people are just so amazing and
creative and have so many
awesome project ideas and collaborations
so in the discord i know that we'll have
papers and research and projects
together that are
maybe even only constituting our lab
participants
but will not be part of the exact
organizational unit
just be people collaborating we have a
discord
and the join link is probably in the
video description and
live chat and here and then there's
twitter inference active
on twitter then um for live streaming
uh if you're watching it it's on youtube
and then if you're
live streaming it then there's this
dashboard for youtube live streaming
and then currently as broadcaster i'm
using the open broadcasting studio
obs project.com and then just that's
what i'm
using right now but the fun part and
just to sort of call back to the roles
of comms is the um the
facilitator and the event organizer in
the broadcaster the participant
it could be one person all doing these
roles for one person
or it could be many people with these
roles and it could be split up across
different expertises and skills
and then lastly aweber is where we have
our
monthly newsletter so there's been two
of them end of january
end of february so far because now it's
march 2nd
and that's going to be just for updates
on our projects and sort of sharing
similar information
to this live stream but just in a
bullet point project by project way okay
any tools thoughts that's sort of the
active lab
stack or just where it is but we know
that some of these platforms are going
to be
closing or changing or new ones come on
to the scene and
so yeah we just are kind of at the spot
we're at
and then as the affordance becomes
salient and preferable while also being
aware of switching costs then
we'll do what we have to do to scale
any other thoughts on tools though oh
stephen go for it
well i was just wondering if there's are
you actively looking for any tools to
bridge any gaps at the moment or you
sort of you feel you've got enough at
the moment like is this
i'm just curious if that's something
that you're trying to look at
i would respond in terms of optimal
experimentation
and optimal foraging on a rapidly
shifting
affordance landscape there's tools that
are just at
working quality today or in six months
that a year ago
we hadn't heard of so by staying
connected
to people with various domain specific
expertise and kind of
use specific expertise we want to stay
attuned to trends
on the tool landscape and then dot tools
is the spot where the people who are
the most interested in that will come
together
to look for internal opportunities for
local and global improvement
like fine-tuning the discord channels or
going to a different
platform for that function so it's a
need-based
engineering approach and then also
once there's again a stable working
version or it seems like the global
reorganization of the tools internally
is off the table for some period of time
or something
then there's more attentional capacity
for external collaboration
okay hashtag future all right
so to kind of recap the next steps for
the lab
the main next steps for the lab are the
next steps within each unit
which we can talk about with i guess we
can just say the edu is
working on improving the terms list and
on
developing the terms list down the road
of ontology
formalism dot coms is interested
in continuing and expanding the current
series which are the
weekly live stream the model stream and
the guest stream
and then also opening up new series or
types of content like audio only bite
sized or
who knows other media that are possible
with tech
and then in dot tools with a two-fold
goal of internal and external tool use
and development
they're currently assessing
needs and um
seeing what can be done as evidenced by
these discussions we're just having
today
as we're heading this is from the point
of view of the admin
as we're heading into our second quarter
of activity we're
looking to focus more on preparing
detailed narratives of active inference
lab
and for participants to help
structure the end of onft
because we're starting on ontology with
the terms list formal documents are
related to tools and we have what we
have and again
we'll locally and globally fine tune as
we need to
and then the tools is for now
the formal documents and communication
channels but that was the whole point
of our paper in 2020 which is for remote
teams and communities
communities of practice however you want
to think about it the affordances for
design
are the ontologies and the formal
documents
because those are the tools that the
team uses
for communication and then what's being
communicated
is heterogeneous it could be text it
could be a
image meme it could be an emoji it could
be a link to something
it can be very very specific pieces of
data
that are getting interpreted in the
context of what the narrative which is
the end part
so o f and t are kind of like the
observables and the systems that we can
actually increment and focus our
attention on and
narrative is something that you can get
meta about and focus
on but really it has to be enacted
and changed through non-equilibrium
steady state
type design not equilibrium steady state
type design
so the reason for this narrative
preparation which also alex
really led the way on with laying out um
participant life cycle
from experience with the system school
we want to
structure the access and
interpretability of lab materials
so people can have their participation
catalyzed so the rate limiting step is
it that they didn't know where this
spreadsheet was or they
solid spreadsheet but then didn't
understand how to get in touch with
something to schedule this time and then
um
the needs for the lab are in the
edu project any participants who are
interested
in ontology and uh education making or
taking coursework
formalisms learning by doing teaching
dot coms
is always looking for participants
looking in uh to areas like writing
teaching connecting audio visual
production
and events co-organizing then
tools we are looking for participants
who are interested in technical
development
computer science user experiences
toolkit
use practices
also accessibility and how tools are
used across different communities
and then the admin are participants who
are interested in
topics like logistics education
communication
tools these are the projects hint
community mentoring and service so we're
just
looking to um our diagram
and to how we can increment people as
our system of interest along this
continuum here
in the context of this evolving
structure
and that will be cool any thoughts on
next steps or
needs for the lab
the last questions are just um kind of
the questions from the regular papers
just
on the inference side what are we
curious about learning more about which
is
kind of an action oriented curiosity
and then how are we wanting to apply
active inference and then all the
questions that we ask about
papers but pretty fun thanks everyone
for the first
quarterly roundtable
pretty fun any last thoughts otherwise
that's good
alright so thanks for participating and
see you later bye